In the same breath that you want to sensationalize me, want to highlight and point out, oh, an officer was killed the other day, which is a rare occurrence across the United States, but let alone in New York. New York police officers have killed at least seven people this year, including a 19-year-old, an NYPD officer killed a 19-year-old in Queens yesterday.
I'm not going to dismiss the loss of the life of an innocent person that wears a uniform to protect us.
But you do, of the 31 people dead at Rikers and the 19-year-old killed yesterday.
I feel like I don't want to take you out of context, and I don't want people to all of a sudden criticize that you're being dismissive of a young man being shot and killed.
Mayor Adams, that's not going to work on me.
I'm not trying to work anything on you.
I lost a member of the police department.
The same way I go to see the mother of an 11-month-old baby that was shot in the head when I first became mayor and I sat in a hospital with her, the same way I go visit these mothers who lose their children to gun violence, I go see them.
Yes, but not the mothers, the people who are dying in Rikers.
Just as I go to see the family member of a slain police officer, I go visit those parents that lose their loved ones to violence.
Are you visiting the family of them?
Do you do that?
First of all, yes, I did.
I held a Riker.
I represented hundreds.
You went to visit the family member of a slain officer?
No, not the slain officer.
Okay, of course you did.
But what about the 19-year-old that was killed yesterday by NYPD in Queens when he called for help?
Have you said anything about that?
Are you visiting them?
Yeah, the, the, the, first of all, that's...
I think you're right that there is a difference between perception and fact and how people feel about safety and the way people feel about the subways.
And I think it's your own rhetoric about the subways that has a lot to do with why people feel scared, despite the fact that millions of people ride the subway every day without incident.
But you've continued to fear monger about crime in the subways.
You've added 2,000 police officers, despite the fact that you've acknowledged that the subways are not that dangerous.
And I think there is, you're right, poor New Yorkers should not be the ones who bear the brunt of this.
But they will if they already have the subway being turned into a place that they have to fear, that there's a National Guard, that there's a hyper-visibility of police, that they're trying to stop people with certain records from even using them.
And now you have this congestion price.
So how do you reconcile that?
Well, let's, let's go before, first of all, I would love to, give me, give me the quotes on my rhetoric, because I'm, I'm lost on that.
Can you give me the quotes?
Oh, that you fear monger about the subways?
Yeah, give me.
Oh, you've consistently done that since the day one of your administration.
One of the first things you did was add 1,000 officers to the subway because you claimed that the subways are unrideable.
Unrideable, you aunt Hochul did this and said how dangerous it is.
And you recently did that when you deployed the National Guard.
Sister, but that's not, that wasn't my question.
Federal monitor who was tasked with ensuring that NYPD is following the law conducted, conducted an analysis.
Came under who?
Conducted an analysis that happened eight years ago, but they're still here monitoring what you're doing.
And they said that you have brought back stop and frisk policies that are worse than they saw even during the Bloomberg era.
But more importantly, they analyzed the neighborhood.
I could show you, the report is available and I know it's been available to you because your spokesperson has commented on it.
They did an analysis of over 10 precincts, 10 different precincts that is factual.
There's a federal monitor reporting to Judge T. Swain on it and presenting information.
They said that, yes, listen, let me finish so you can peel it back.
They conducted an analysis of 10 different precincts.
And of the stops of 10 different precincts, they found that 97% of them, by the way, of the neighborhood safety teams that were disbanded in 2020 because of the disproportionate abuse against black and Hispanic people that you revived,
they analyzed 10 of those different neighborhood safety teams and found that they're conducting 97% of their stops on black and brown people and a quarter of them are unconstitutional.
And that's what the federal monitor said, not me.
Yeah, yeah.